<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Marad Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.radoszewski.pl/tags/programming/feed/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Marad Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.radoszewski.pl/tags/programming/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Use Vim if you like your job!</title>
      <link>http://blog.radoszewski.pl/post/dont-use-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 09:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.radoszewski.pl/post/dont-use-vim/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re like me you probably like to make your life easier wherever and whenever it is possible. I
also like to pick up the gauntlet and try something new and challenging. This is why I started to
use Vim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a professional programmer. I&amp;rsquo;m paid to edit code. No wonder why I wanted my editing to be
quicker and easier.  I knew that Vim has it&amp;rsquo;s worshipers even though it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; old so I thought
there must be something great about it.  I&amp;rsquo;ve started to learn the Vim ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now - about a year later I can tell you &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t use Vim if you like your job!&lt;/strong&gt; Assuming, of course,
that your job has something to do with computers and editing text ;) You can ask me&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Vim for a year now I can edit text quickly and easily. I rarely have to reach out
with my hands even for the cursor keys - not to mention grabbing a mouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is wrong then? Well&amp;hellip; I can&amp;rsquo;t edit text or code with anything other than Vim now. Literally
&lt;strong&gt;every&lt;/strong&gt; other editor is just simple useless notepad to me! Thankfully vast majority of editors
support Vim-Mode editing. Honestly I was surprised with how many programs allow you to edit content
like Vim. The only problem is that Vim is huge.  It has hundreds of functions waiting for you to use
them. Vim-Mode in most programs allows you to do only basic things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my job I use IntelliJ IDEA which (thanks to havens) have a plugin that enables Vim-like editing,
and it&amp;rsquo;s actually quite good. It&amp;rsquo;s a whole lot slower than real Vim but I believe it&amp;rsquo;s a fair trade
for features it provides.  Actually I use IntelliJ IDEA for only three reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;auto completion,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;organizing imports,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactoring variable/method/class names.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact I could live without the refactoring, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to give up auto completion&amp;hellip; Trust me,
I&amp;rsquo;ve tried&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum up. I&amp;rsquo;d recommend using Vim to everyone if only all editors had great support for it. Only
problem is that if you get used to editing text the Vim-way you&amp;rsquo;ll never look at any other editor
ever again. To be honest Vim was one of the reasons I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped writing on my previous blog. I just
didn&amp;rsquo;t want to use this Wordpress&amp;rsquo;s online editor.  I could never make the post look like I desired
and it was just plain simple notepad. Believe me that I had to remove a lot of things like &lt;code&gt;jjcip&lt;/code&gt;
from the text&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: If you are working with text - try Vim on your own responsibility. Vim will spoil you and you
will never want to use any other editor!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you! (and yes - I wrote this in Vim)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>